Finding Aid for Evaluation and Examinations Division (University of Michigan) records, 1927-1971
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Project Files 1947-1964
  - Project 35. Undergraduate Performance in LSA of students graduating from other University units February 1960 (Box 2)
  - Nursing -- Prediction Study General Folder, 1953-54 (Box 3)
  - Test-Score Card Tabulations for Nurses, Fall 1953 (Box 3)
  - Psychiatric Nursing -- Studies, 1955-56 (Box 3)
  - Pharmacy Recent Studies of the performance of Pharmacy Students at UM. February 1956 (Box 3)
  - Analysis of Grades of Freshmen Pharmacy Students May 1951 (Box 3)
  - 21. SQT, Regents -- Alumni Scholarship Applicant Norms for undated (Box 3)
  - Regents Alumni, Outstate Administration vs. Bureau Administration February 1951 Compiled December 1951 (Box 3)
  - Social Work -- Validation of Graduate Aptitude Test 1949 (Box 3)
  - Astronomy 11 -- Comparison of subjective and objective tests 5/26/1960 (Box 3)
  - Project 125 -- Quality of Athletes Senate Committee 3/27/1959 (Box 3)
  - Project 29 Description of Counseling Division Clientele 1958 (Box 3)
  - Participation in Standardization of Forms C and D of CQT. Milholland 1959 (Box 3)
  - Detroit Public Schools Citizens Committee 1958 (Box 3)
  - Michigan Norms for DAT 1956-1957 (Box 3)
  - CQT -- Standardization of Forms C, D in cooperation with Educational Testing Services 1959 (Box 3)
  - Administration of new form of Graduate Record Exam in Chemistry 2/6/1963 (Box 3)
  - Project 184. Standardization of new forms of Graduate Record Examinations March 1961 (Box 3)
  - Administration of Questionnaire for High School Graduate Study 4/18/1963 (Box 3)
  - Study of undergraduate LSA performance of students graduating from other units 1957 (Box 3)
  - Study of undergraduate LSA performance of students graduating from other units completed October 1959 (Box 3)
  - Project 207. Standardization of Lorge-Thorndike Intelligence Tests, Spring 1962 (Box 3)
  - Administration of selection test for the Peace Corps. Milholland 1962 (Box 3)
  - Project 200. Use of Test Data by Colleges Paper for APGA 4/18/1962 (Box 3)
  - Project 163. Follow-up of top 10 percent of Michigan High School Graduating Classes 1960-1964 (Box 3)
  - Project 159 Comparison of SAT Scores made in High School and During Orientation Week by 317 freshmen 1955 (Box 3)
  - Project 175. Test Norms for Bay City, Jackson, Muskegon, Port Huron October 1960 (Box 3)
  - Test Review for Mental Measurements Yearbook 1958-1960 (Box 3)
  - Transfer Students Graduating in June 1962 (Box 3)
  - Michigan Municipal League Public Safety Officer 1959 (Box 3)
  - SAT Median Total Scores in Various Concentration Fields in LSA 10/26/1960 (Box 3)
  - Request from Yale for SAT data and data on number of graduates in various fields of LSA and Engineering 1956-1958 (Box 3)
  - Physical Science Distribution Courses of Non-Science Majors, Freshmen 1955 (Box 3)
  - Coop English Test C2:T Reading Comp. (Speed and Level Versus Rate and Accuracy of Reading Test Scores) 1956 (Box 3)
  - SQT (V&Q) Distribution of scores for Fall 1957 freshmen (Michigan residents) also proposal for SQT prep. 12/7/56, 1957 (Box 3)
  - 19. GPAs of Junior College Transfers 1956-1957 (Box 3)
  - Median GPAs for the 1955-56 Academic Year in several units of the University at each class level 1955-1956 (Box 3)
- Test Manuals and Guides 1949-1960
  The Test Manuals and Guides, 1949-1960 series .33 ft.) contains bound folders containing tests and test instructions, proctor instructions, bulletins and normalization tables for interpretation, and memoranda on creating test questions, using the tests and test results and placement guidelines and using IBM machines for the mechanization of test scoring. Also includes freshman orientation ephemera, including mailings, schedules and agenda for testing.
  - ACE Psychological Examination 1949 Edition (Box 4)
  - Interpreting Test Scores a Manual on the Freshman Testing Program (General) Copy 112 1954 (Box 4)
  - Michigan Mathematics Placement Test 1956 Edition (Box 4)
  - Freshman Testing "Old" Materials 1956-1959 (Box 4)
  - Student Survey on Counseling Tables 1957 (Box 4)
  - Mechanization of the Freshman Orientation Testing Program at the University of Michigan 1959 (Box 4)
  - Directions for "Morning" Tests Summer Orientation Program June -- August, 1960 (Box 4)
- Statistical Reports 1947-1962
  The Statistical Reports, 1947-1963 series (.33 ft.) consists of bound reports produced by the Division of Evaluation and Examinations in relation to various projects completed. Reports contain tables, graphs, published papers, and survey tools used by the projects' investigators. The series is arranged chronologically.
  - Statistical Reports I 1947-1957 (Box 4)
  - Statistical Reports II 1957 (Box 4)
  - Statistical Reports III 1958, 1959, 1960 (Box 4)
  - Statistical Reports IV 1960-1962 (Box 4)
  - Statistical Reports V 1962 (Box 4)
- Benno Fricke Materials 1956-1971
  - Paper: "Tests, Students, Standards and Admissions Officers" 1957 (Box 4)
  - Research proposal to U.S. Office of Education, Department of Health, Education and Welfare 1958 (Box 4)
  - Report: "Recent Research Results with the Opinion, Attitude and Interest Survey" 1959 (Box 4)
  - "6A" and "6B" Reports, data tables and correspondence related to freshmen testing 1956-1964 (Box 4)
  - Report: "Graduate School Foreign Language Requirement Study," 1966 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence and revisions to report "Academic Quality of Entering Freshmen and the Admissions Problem," 1958, 1970 (Box 4)
  - "10B" Correspondence, reports and ephemera relating to OAIS testing 1962-1971 (Box 4)
  - "15A" Correspondence and reports related to the testing and student quality 1965-1971 (Box 4)
  - "14" Correspondence and lecture ephemera for faculty on grading students 1958-1970 (Box 4)